# BEN HASSINE MOHAMED DHIA

Full-Stack Developer

- benhassine.med.dhia@gmail.com
- 00351 93 704 0156

Porto, Portugal

in bhmeddhiaa



Version Français

# CAREER SUMMARY

With years of experience as a developer, I'm driven by a continual love of learning and innovation. My career is marked by collaborative efforts to develop web-based applications and improve product quality through code optimisation and proactive problem-solving.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Freelance

### **Full-Stack Developer**

12-2024 - Present

#### Frontend Development:

- Develop the Fantasy Tunisia mobile application using React Native for crossplatform compatibility (iOS and Android).
- Design and develop a high-performance, user-friendly mobile application using React

# **Backend Development:**

- Develop and maintain a scalable backend using GoLang.
- Implement RESTful APIs to handle user data, team management, and real-time
- Ensure secure and efficient data handling with Supabase. Integration:
- Integrate frontend and backend components effectively to deliver a cohesive
- · Work with third-party APIs and libraries to enhance the application's functionality. Address and resolve application issues promptly.

# **Technologies used:**









Material UI

# **Backend Developer**

08-2024 - 11-2024

- Designed and developed RESTful APIs to handle requests and responses efficiently.
- Designed and maintained relational database schemas in MySQL.
- Used tools like APIDOG.com for documenting APIs.
- Performed unit tests on the server using Termius.

# Kuda Website

# **Technologies used:**









project goals, deliverables, timelines, and success criteria.



# **Project Manager**

12-2023 - 08-2024

- Defining Project Scope: Work closely with founders and stakeholders to define
- Sprint Planning: Lead sprint planning sessions, ensuring that the team has clear, actionable tasks and understands priorities.
- Iteration Reviews and Retrospectives: Conduct regular reviews and retrospectives to evaluate progress, gather feedback, and continuously improve processes.
- Team Collaboration: Facilitate collaboration between development, design, marketing, and sales to ensure that project goals are met cohesively.

# Digital Natives Web Site

# **Full-Stack Developer**

**Digital Natives** 

**Digital Natives** 

**Digital Natives** 

02-2023 - 11-2023

- Develop the backend for a web application similar to Airbnb using Node.js, Express.js, and Sequelize. Implement APIs such as OpenAI and FastForex.
- Perform unit tests on the server using Termius.
- · Document the project using APIDOG.com.
- Develop an admin dashboard with a Material UI template.

# LANGUAGE

French

Fluent

**English** Fluent

Arabic

Native Language

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Full Stack Javascript**

Developer

RebootKamp (RBK) 08/2022 - 02/2023

# Master degree in

management

Leaders University - Tunisia 09/2014 - 10/2016

# Bachelor's degree in business IT

Faculty of economics and management - Tunisia 09/2010 - 06/2013

# Baccalaureate in Management IT

High school 7 November -Tunisia 09/2009 - 06/2010

# **DEVELOPMENT** STACK

# **Programming Languages**

GoLang

Python

JavaScript TypeScript

#### Frontend Libraries & **Frameworks**

React Native / React

Next.js

## **Backend Frameworks & Databases**

Node JS

Express JS

MySQL, Sequelize

Supabase

MongoDB

# **Others**

superhost.com.tn Git Unlayer Termius Technologies used: phpMyAdmin ApiDog CI/CD NodeJS Express Redux JavaScript JWT React **Jenkins** Jest Freelance 08-2022 - 10-2023 **SKILLS** Project 1: Sales Store Dashboard Full-Stack Developer • Develop the backend for an Admin dashboard using Node.js, Express.js, and Problem-solving Sequelize. Team Work • Develop an admin dashboard with a Material UI template. Communication skills **Technologies used:** Creativity NodeJS Express Sequelize JavaScript React Material UI Client Interaction Documentation Project 2: Tawelti Full-Stack Developer RebootKamp (RBK) **Project Management** • Integrate Cloudinary with React Native and Google Maps. • Develop the backend for the mobile application using Node.js, Express.js, and Sequelize. • Designed and developed an admin dashboard. • Collaborate on data analysis and improve SQL queries of high volume databases.

React Native NodeJS **Full-Stack Developer** 

Express

**Technologies used:** 

PROMOCUISINE (Cuisina + Marmotek)

06-2020 - 08-2022

• Displays key sales metrics such as total sales, number of deals closed, and topperforming products.

JavaScript

JWT

• Shows the top-performing sales representatives based on various criteria.

Sequelize

• A section to manage the list of products/services, including details like pricing and description.

# Technologies used:



